

RISHPATEL

FULL STACK WEB AND MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER

"Rishi goes above and beyond when given a challenge and is never afraid to take on leadership roles." - Nazariy Dumanskyy (Manager)

rprishi08@gmail.com



+1819-576-1628



Ottawa, ON, Canada



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/rishi-patel-65a636125/



IN A NUTSHELL

Pro at UI/UX, web development, and making things look beautiful.

WHAT DO I BRING TO TABLE?

I've got 1+ years of diverse leadership and management experience ready to be put to use. My primary focus is on building Front End Web Applications, Native Mobile Applications, Integrations, Alexa Skills, and Google Actions. My background in graphic design, and web development allows me to fuse both the art and technology world together in perfect harmony making me a valuable asset for any team.

I DON'T WANT...

...Just another job. I want to solve problems and make people's lives easier in a community that shares my passion for technology.

THE TECH

JavaScript(ES6), React JS, Bootstrap, Node JS, Firebase Firestore, React Native, HTML5, CSS3, MongoDB, Photoshop, Illustrator, XD and more.



EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER | CLEVER PROGRAMMER

APRIL 2020 - PRESENT

One of the first and only student to join the team out of the entire community of 2000 students. Lead a team of JavaScript Coaches to constantly improve students success. Built a complete website from scratch for the coaches, developed multiple sales pages and more.

UI/UX DESIGNER & DEVELOPER | CANADA BORDER SERVICES AGENCY

JAN 2020 - APRIL 2020

I was in one of the two teams from the whole college who was hired to work with the government. We developed a voice application for Canadian travellers to teach them about border rules and regulations. We developed Amazon Alexa Skill and Google Action to improve the search speed from 4 mins to less than a min.

"Rishi was a key member of the development team. He always demonstrated excellent client communication, solid technical skills and was always accommodating." - Ranjan Banerjee (Senior Strategic Advisor at CBSA)

OTHER NOTABLE POSITIONS:

- FREELANCE DEVELOPER | FREELANCER.COM
- PROGRAMMING TUTOR



EDUCATION AND AWARDS

GRADAUTED - APRIL 2020 | ALGONQUIN COLLEGE

DEAN'S HONOURS LIST

Awarded and listed in the Dean's Honours list for excellent academic acheivent with 3.9 GPA.

NOTEWORTHY PROJECTS

CBSA-Helper - A voice assistant for Canada Border Services Agency (CBSA)

JAN 2020 - APRIL 2020

- With a team, developed a Google Action and Amazon Alexa skill to teach about border rules and regulations
- Involved in project managing, developing the Google Action, and the API
- Improved the user's search speed by 80% from 5 to 1 min
- Implemented the UX process to increase productivity by 20%
- Simplified user experience by storing user's conversations in Firebase Firestore
- Technologies Used: Node JS, Firebase Firestore, Dialogflow, Alexa console, Twilio, Sendgrid, and SMTP
- Github: https://github.com/pate0672/CBSA-Helper
- Youtube Presentation: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aWgBr_PKGzU

Real Time React Chat App

OCT 2019 - DEC 2019

- Built a chat application to allow users to talk in real time.
- Was involved in the whole project from start to finish between researching, testing, and development
- Implemented back-end to have a real time and dynamic user experience
- Deployed front-end on Netlify and Backend on Heroku to make it live for everyone to use
- Technologies Used: React JS, Node JS, Socket IO, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6) and HTML5
- Github: https://github.com/pate0672/React-Chat-App
- Live Link:

https://5e660e1b7e060051e0e02cc7--react-chat-app-rishi.netlify.app/

Facebook Messenger Clone

MAY 2020 - JULY 2020

- Worked on the front-end as well as back-end from scratch
- Developed a Facebook Messenger Clone very similar to Facebook Messenger
- Implemented material UI and Firebase Firestore for smooth and dynamic user experience
- Technologies Used: React JS, JavaScript (ES6), Firebase Firestore, Material UI, CSS3 and HTML5
- Live Link: https://facebook-messenger-clone-b72b1.firebaseapp.com/

Online Pizza Ordering Portal

JUNE 2019 - JULY 2019

- Lead a team for developing an online pizza ordering portal called "Pizza Zizza"
- Highly focused on front-end, back-end, and user authentication
- Improved users experience by 15% by easy to use User Interface
- Technologies Used: JavaScript (ES6), Node JS, Mongo DB, edumedia (college server), CSS3 and HTML5
- Github: https://github.com/pate0672/Pizza-Zizza-Frontend



REFERENCE

RANJAN BANERJEE - SENIOR STRATEGIC ADVISORE AT CBSA

Email: ranjan@banerjee.ca